ANDREW CRAIG Front End Web Developer

ABOUT:

Hello, my name is Andrew, I'm a Front End Web Developer based in Toronto. I am passionate about creating detailed, efficient and well styled work. I'm also interested in workflow speed (Emmet, SCSS and React) and programming knowledge that saves time. During my studies I worked in agile environments doing paired programming, group projects or working alone. I'm self motivated and dedicated to learning and growing in the industry. Outside of work I play guitar and read sci fi books. I've also recorded over 60 songs! Please feel free to contact me!

- (416) 826-4854
- info@andrewcraigdev.com
- andrewcraigdev.com
- in linkedin.com/in/andrewcraigdeveloper
- Toronto, ON

EDUCATION:

Front End Web Development • 2019 - 2021 Juno School of Technology, Toronto, ON

- Web Development Immersive
- Web Dev Fundamentals
- Javascript Fundamentals

Bachelor of Arts • 2002

Concordia University, Montreal, QC

SKILLS:

- HTML5
- Accessibility
- CSS/SCSS
- Responsive Design
- Javascript
- Team work
- React
- Scheduling
- REST API
- Management
- FirebaseJQUERY
- Sales

PROJECTS:

Trivia Time

React - SCSS/HTML

NBACodeStars

Javascript - SCSS/HTML

Refrigeration Versification

React - API - Firebase - CSS/HTML

Oscar Finder

React - Firebase - CSS/HTML

CageFinder

Javascript - CSS/HTML

EXPERIENCE:

Front End Web Developer • 2018 - Present

Freelance Developer

- Created programming work in a wide range of front end coding languages.
- Took on multiple projects with colleagues or alone to produce accessible, responsive and well designed web projects.
- Worked on deadlines, handling design pivots and with client instruction to produce accurate, quality work.
- Spent time outside of work studying to expand skills and acquire new ones.

Manager • 2006 - 2020

Artist Manager, Toronto

- Problem solved complex, overlapping issues including: financing, scheduling, recording, tour dates, music video production, branding and interviews
- Built working relationships with hundreds of industry professionals, managers, label reps, venue owners and artists
- Helped negotiate recording contracts with multiple labels
- Obtained excellent experience in marketing and social media
- Produced and directed five music videos

Product Sales • 2008 - 2019

New Roots Herbal, Toronto

- Memorized the complex details of over ninety products and educated clients on their use and purpose
- Problem solved the personal issues of thousands of clients regarding their health and supplements.
- Maintained working relationships with the management and staff of nineteen business's across the GTA
- Achieved and exceeded sales quotas on time or before deadlines
- Spent time outside of work reading up on trends and products to improve work performance.